in the pocket on third and long. Ross
sacked by Chris Jones. Stone cold caught
by Kelsey inside the 10. Inside the
five. KELSEY LEAPS. TOUCHDOWN. KAREEM
HUNT AT THE 10. Angling to the five INTO
THE END ZONE LEFT SIDE AND IT is good.
Good. Here comes a rush and he's GOING
TO GO DOWN. GEORGE CARLUS.
[music]
Will the Chiefs lose this one 16-13? Now
losing five out of six games since being
five and three on Halloween. Mitch Altus
with you. Voice of the Chiefs along with
senior team reporter Matt McMullen. Woo.
This one. Uh first of all, let's start
with the injury to Patrick Mahomes.
We're going to get an update from coach
here very shortly. uh and he will uh lay
all that out because we'll go to the
podium and hear from coach. But the
Chiefs led 13-3 with 38 seconds to go in
the second quarter. And you thought even
with Chu Godri at tackle and and playing
Esapole at tackle and Mike Caliendo at
right guard, they might pull a game out
like this.
>> Yeah, it seemed like they might. Uh
unfortunately, this game like just about
every one of our other losses this year,
uh came down to missed opportunities. Um
it was right there for the Chiefs. uh up
10 points in this game in the first
half, but even being down by three
points in the third and fourth quarter,
we drove into Chargers territory on our
two final drives. Both drives ended with
interceptions. We had chances in this
game. You know, I'm proud of our guys
for fighting all year. Uh we talked
about on field pass how all of our
losses this year have been close. We've
been in every single game this year. U
unfortunately, sometimes it's just not
your season and uh I don't think it's
our season unfortunately this year. I
think I'm right about this. The Chiefs
have won 18 of the last 19 when they've
led at halftime. Although the vibe here
was a little bit different because it's
the old backto back. Uh Chiefs go up
with 38 seconds to go by 10. But then
the Chargers get a touchdown with 5
seconds to go in the half and you knew
they were going to get the ball to start
the third quarter and then they end up
tying the game on a field goal. But then
two three and outs. Chiefs only had four
possessions in the second half. Two
three and outs and two picks.
>> Yeah, that double dip that we've talked
about all season talking about the
Chiefs. Unfortunately, that bit us here
today. The defense overall played well
enough to win. I think you hold the
Chargers to only 16 points here at home.
But yeah, that touchdown at the end of
the first half when they get down the
field and score and 33 seconds, I think
I mean that was the play that I think
we'll look back on and say that's kind
of where the game was lost. Uh the
Chargers score I think 13 unanswered and
that was the big part of that. So that's
the kind of thing you can't allow when
you're playing for your season. Uh this
was a playoff game like we talked about
and you can't allow plays like that in a
playoff game. Unfortunately, that's what
happened.
>> To your point though, the Chiefs came
roaring back even down 1613. They're
driving for at least a game tying field
goal and then Patrick Mahomes tried to
find Kareem Hunt on a wheel route. Deion
Henley made a great play on the
interception, but Taekquin Thornton had
two catches for 42 yards. Super tough
catches. We talk about tight window
throws, uh tight window catches. he made
to to give the Chiefs an opportunity
there. The guys, he's a battler. And
then Kelsey, we saw him warrior up on
the last potential game-tying drive.
>> Yeah, I talked about how this team
fought all year long and I don't want
that to be lost in this season. Our guys
fought all season and they fought here
today. Patrick Mahomes on that touchdown
drive on our opening series, 12 yardd
scramble, not an easy play. He fought
for that play and Mahomes fought till
the very end and I have full confidence
he would have let us down to a at least
a game time field goal there at the end
if he hadn't gotten hurt. This team
fought. There was no giving up on this
team. And you know, you talk about
Taekwon Thornton. Think about all the
craziness of that couple of minutes
there where it was third and 16. There
was penalties. There was a targeting
call. Uh Tony Jefferson gets
disqualified. Like all kinds of
craziness. Mahomes kept just firing,
leading our guys down there. Our guys
fought. Again, the margin for error is
so slim in the NFL. And unfortunately,
the margin there has been just short for
us just about every time this year. It's
it's unfortunate. But our guys fought.
They did.
>> And Menu fought.
>> Yeah.
>> I had every confidence in him. He's
going to drive at least [laughter] a
field goal. Maybe might have had a
touchdown and win the game. But anyway,
the the big news is Patrick Mahomes
injured on the final drive of the game.
Let's go to the podium and get an update
with Andy Reid.
>> All right. Um, as far as the injuries
go, um, Patrick hurt his left knee.
We'll get an MRI, uh, tomorrow or this
evening, whenever they [snorts] get him
in there. And then, uh, Jaylen Moore,
uh, likewise, left knee, and then
Thornton, um, got hit in the head and
and, um, you know, we'll just see where
he's at, but, he's in the protocol right
now. Um, listen, all in all, we came up
short. you you know we on both sides of
the ball and special teams uh we had a
few mistakes and that ends up costing
you against a good football team. I
appreciate the effort of the guys and
stepping up uh um you know playing hard
and aggressive some some positions were
uh backup guys to backup guys and they
battled their tail off. So um that's
appreciated our fans. We appreciate them
showing up in the cold here and
supporting us. best fans in the National
Football League. So, um, but with that,
we've got to do better. You know, you
get opportunities in the red zone, more
field position, you you got to take
advantage of that. If it's special
teams, we got to create field position.
And then defensively, we've got to
maintain it. And so, um, in those those
cases, we we weren't quite good enough
in all three phases. And again, that's
my responsibility to make sure that you
don't have these kind of mistakes. And
so, um, I was I'll look in the mirror
first on this. But anyways, with that,
time's yours.
>> Andy, with Patrick, is there fear this
could be something serious?
>> Um, [clears throat]
I don't know, but I mean, it didn't look
good. So, I mean, you guys saw it, so
it's um we'll just see where where it
goes. Yeah.
>> How tough the situations after Gardner
stepped into?
>> Yeah, that's a tough that's tough deal,
but you know, he's he's a big boy. I
mean, he's done it before. He's played
before, so he he understands the role.
>> Andy, what what's the locker room like
for you today going in there after this
long?
>> Yeah, guys are down. They busted their
butt to win the game, you know, and I
wouldn't expect anything less. Uh
[snorts]
so, you know, it's not a not a great
feeling. Uh I wouldn't expect it to be
after after losing a game.
>> Just for you, your own [clears throat]
your own thoughts going in there,
knowing what was at stake today and and
what
>> Yeah, sure. Listen, I mean, yeah, I
[clears throat] mean, I can't tell you
I'm happy, you know, by So, it's uh it's
a tough deal there, you know, when when
you deal with that, but same time, we've
got a few more games here we got to take
care of. So,
>> it was tough [clears throat] that
Patrick would usually walk us through,
but the interception that he had on on
third down, was a play that probably
just throw away or what you see on
>> Yeah, I mean, yeah, he probably want
that one back. Yeah, you didn't want to
throw an interception there. Um, you
thought Kareem could potentially make a
play on a linebacker, you know, but
that's what happened.
Seemed like a big momentum going for
half. The Chargers got down there.
>> Yeah. Well, there was a return, you
know, so you get a big return and
that's not good. That's kind of that
flipped some switches there, you know,
and then they get the ball the first
series. So they score on the last series
of the half, come back first series and
get points. So that's not good.
>> A lot of guys get hurt, come back in the
game. So it seemed like that spirit just
was all in on this. It was kind of a
rough game.
>> Yeah, it was physical. So yeah, the guys
I appreciate that that's u
uh they battled um wasn't
[clears throat] for a lack of effort or
battling. It was just had some mistakes
cost us. What was your thoughts on put
the hit on taekwond and just the
exchange afterwards there?
>> Uh the league, you know, they took care
of it. So um
but um
it was what what happened.
It's one of those kind of hits. There
were a couple of those. They got him on
that one.
>> Andy, sorry. Where does your mind go?
Obviously now you guys are eliminated
from the playoffs for this whole season.
Just what where does your mind go to?
thinking about what's happened the last
few week.
>> Yeah. Well, we got to take care of
business the next few games. So, I mean,
I'm just coming off the field. My mind
was on this game here and taking care of
it there and you know, I wanted to come
come out different obviously. So, um I
haven't gone too much further than that.
>> Sam, you guys are obviously playing with
three backup offensive linemen. I know
you guys prepare them to be starters,
but still how much does that just limit
what you can do in passing? Yeah, I mean
the posit listen, I'm I'll find a
positive in that. So that these young
guys had an opportunity to play, get a
chance to see see what they can do. I
thought they did a respectable job in
there. Um
so that's good as we as we grow here as
a team.
specifically with both Cole and Chu Chu
in particular being an international
pathway player. What you see
[clears throat]
what you know significance is to have a
guy like that.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Ch's come a long way
from uh not playing a lot of football
and he's a very good athlete, smart kid
and um you know it's great that he had a
chance to get in and compete.
Okay, thanks coach.
>> All right, good.
Third and 11. Herbert crouching down a
little lower. This time Chiefs are
blitzing on the backside of Herbert. HIT
AS HE THROWS IT BACK. INTERCEPTED AT THE
30. THE CHARGERS PICKED OFF ON THE NEAR
SIDE. THIS TIME THE CHIEFS DIDN'T DROP
THE PICK AND PICKED OFF BY Ashton
Galotti. THE ROOKIE OUT OF LOUISVILLE
[screaming]
GETS HIS FIRST PICK.
If you want to get excited about the
future starting now, uh this guy will be
at the top of the list. Ashton Gelotti,
difficult game, but an incredible game
for you. Uh let's go to your
interception and what happened on that
play.
>> Um it was a a a call where I had a drop.
Um thankful that I think it was Mike
Edwards but one of our DBs or hit
Herbert had to throw a little bad ball
and it kind of just seemed like it
floated up in space for like minutes and
you know it's a play that came to me so
I got to make the most of it catch it
and try to make something happen. And we
saw it as early as rookie mini camp and
going all the way back, you being able
to drop and not just rush or defend the
run that uh what about that play for you
and did you do a lot of it at
Louisville? Cuz I remember you told me
you didn't do a whole lot of it there,
did you?
>> I I only dropped like twice in my entire
career in Louisville. Um it just I mean
we weren't really a drop in team for my
side.
>> Yeah.
>> So I was a rush in. So but you know you
got to learn, you got to adapt
>> well and you stay disciplined. and a
half sack in this game. Uh to stay
disciplined against Herbert because he
had hurt teams with his legs. What about
staying disciplined uh in your rush
lane?
>> Yeah. Um we obviously know he's a he's a
honey old guy. Similar like how Aaron
Rogers is. Uh he's going to step up if
you give him that B gap. So uh we were
just trying to do our best to just make
him throw from a well. Um and if we're
going to allow him to run at the B, trap
it, make him think that there's a B and
know get back in it. So, uh, I think we
did a pretty good job overall just again
containing him in the quarter, uh, in
the pocket, eliminating his ability to
run. So,
>> you're really not a rookie anymore, not
this late in the season handling, uh,
this uh, going to six and eight. Um, and
where you feel responsibility on the
defense to work ahead and try to win
next week. What about that dynamic? Um,
obviously, you know, again, it's tough
loss today, but I mean, we still got uh
we got games left, you know, and no
matter uh whatever we're going to put
that aside and we're just going to play
the game one at a time, one game at a
time. So, um you know, got a good
opportunity coming up. Got to get after
him and, you know, do our thing.
>> Again, a very, very bright future, a
bright now, uh in the present. Ashton
Gelotti
It's tough. It's tough. I mean, any game
you lose, um, is tough. We're all
competitors here, especially me, you
know, especially with so much as state.
It was tough.
>> You thought you was already on your mind
that you guys would be out of the
playoffs when you came off the field?
>> I think the score was 13 and 13 or 13
and 10. So, still had a fighting chance.
Um, are we out of the playoffs?
We are okay
guys
back in
that we have a lot of guys who is very
resilient in our locker room.
>> [clears throat]
>> competitive and you know we all knew it
was at stake. We all wanted to be a part
of this game. We all was looking forward
to it. Unfortunately, we didn't get the
outcome that we hoped for, but you know,
everyone battled
like you didn't know for sure. How does
that sink in with you know?
>> Every year is a journey, man. And um
success is rented every year. Every year
you get to rent success and sometimes it
don't go the way you plan for it to go
and it's it's a it's a learning curve
for for for you guys. You know what I
mean? Especially us. I think we learned
a lot on this year. Um and we understand
the fact that
in order to be successful, man, it's a
everyday thing. It's not on one week uh
put in and next week. No, it's a
consistent thing. And we got a lot of
guys coming back and long [snorts] as
they know that it's rented every year.
Just cuz the last year team uh made it
to the Super Bowl, that doesn't
guarantee a success. You know what I
mean? And um you know, we got three more
games, which um we got to finish strong
still as competitors, as um employees of
this organization. I think it's
important to finish strong, play with
pride, most importantly, play for
yourself. um the name on the back of
your jersey, but also the name on the
front of your jersey. So, I think it's
going to be competitive for us and we
gonna keep on going. Something to build
off on. Looking forward to next year.
>> Chris, how you
def
[clears throat]
>> It's December, man. It's been a year of
football. Um almost a year of football.
So, everyone is battling something
whether it's a nagging energy, I mean
injury, whether it's big, small, you
know, we're all battling something. Um,
so for me, it's about if I can play, I
can play, you know, and getting back on
the field or getting myself in a
position to where I can play and utilize
my skill set.
>> You guys called time out and you guys
getting back on the field like they
called time out to make sure
I didn't know. I didn't know. I heard
that when I was on the sideline and
coach Reed told me to call timeout
because of that, but I didn't know. I
didn't know.
>> What happened with the play?
>> We got off the field. Call off silence.
Got the first down. Three more plays. We
was off the field. You know, you
remember. Okay. [snorts]
>> Last one.
>> Did you see after the game um after his
injury
>> just hugged him man that's my brother
would been through so much and you know
we can be mad at oursel and we can ask
God why but at times it's more so a
lesson that you know you've been taught
along the journey and we'll be selfish
to ask God why
why right now why this more so
understand it build from it we love Pat
that's why it's Pat Mahomes
>> and how acclimated did you feel right
away?
>> Uh yeah, no I feel felt very comfortable
to go in and you know execute the
offense. Um you know hate that
situation. Um hate that couldn't deliver
and get us win and keep our hopes alive.
But um you know
>> what' you see on the interception?
>> Uh they man coverage. Um tried to make
you know take a shot to tra probably
should have kept moving. Gardner, you've
been in the room with Patrick. Just how
frustrating has this last week been
offensive?
>> Yeah, it's very frustrating, man. It's
been It's been hard to watch for Pat.
Like, that dude puts so much into it. I
don't think I've ever respected anybody
I play with more. I've never seen
anybody I play with give so much of
themselves to the team. Um, and to not
get the results is hard. Um, but I have
more confidence in him than anybody to
come back and be better than ever.
>> Wonder what you see from him just the
last few weeks.
>> Uh, Z just shows up every day, you know,
every play, every workday, just giving
it his best, trying to lead and um,
yeah, he's the best.
>> You've been on a few different teams.
This team's six and eight, but you still
feel like this team had more potential
over these last 14 weeks. This team is
better than what it's record.
>> Yeah. I don't know. I mean, we're six
and eight, you know. Probably could have
been something else.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't think you did see Patrick
afterwards or if you did
>> not to the locker room. Yeah.
>> You know, on the sideline watching this
game and then going in there, so many
guys got hurt, came back in the game,
all that. Did you kind of feel the
importance of this, the guys going out
there and laying on the line?
>> I mean, we got guys doing that every
week. Um, I think Pat leads the charge
with that. Puts it out um every week. I
mean, we got so many guys that are
battling. That's that what this time of
year is about. Uh, it's been awesome to
see how many guys go give themselves a
chance to give our team a chance and um,
you know, I look for guys to continue to
do that.
>> I know everyone obviously for the best
with Patrick, but just there are three
games left. How comfortable do you feel
you did the team during practice to get
that guy?
>> Yeah, I felt comfortable. I'll do
whatever the coaches ask of me and we'll
go try to win some games.
>> Sounds like you have a lot of respect
for for Pat. So, was it hard to
compartmentalize worried maybe fear
about what what might be done on him and
you try to take the field in a key
situation? Yeah, I mean that's kind of
the job you're in. You know,
unfortunately for me to play that's what
happens and like you got to
compartmentalize allows obviously get
back to the locker room and that's the
most concerning thing and just uh yeah
just wish best for him.
>> You said you saw in the locker room how
were his spirits afterwards?
>> Yeah, he's down man obviously you know
it's tough game uh but it's up to you at
this point but um you know nobody's
better for it.
>> Thanks for appreciate it.
[clears throat]
Well, we've not been in this territory
uh for a decade. Really, 11 seasons back
to 2014 because now the Chiefs u aren't
headed to the playoffs. But what do you
do in the next three games? There's
three games to go. Starting with the
game at Tennessee a week from today and
we're seeing some signs. N Williams
shows some spark. Ashelotti, we had him
on. He showed some real promise. That
interception was big time in the pass
rush. But you start to look at all those
things now because honestly 2026 starts
right now.
>> Yeah, it does. Uh listen, this is a
bummer. We don't want to be in this
situation. But one of the reasons the
Chiefs have been so successful over the
years is they take advantage of
situations and opportunities. We've
struggled to take advantage of
opportunities this year on the field,
but now we actually have an opportunity
where we can use live reps and real
games to evaluate some young players on
this team and see where this team can go
moving forward. And Ashton Gelotti is a
great example where I think he was the
player of the game here today. A great
interception out in coverage. Uh also
that big sack uh when he had great
discipline when Herbert was trying to do
the the quarterback draw, right? And go
up the middle, try to rush for a first
down. Gelotti stuck with him and sacked
him on that play. Great play by Ashton
Gelotti. He is a an ascending player for
us. So now get him some more reps,
right? Get null Williams some more reps.
Let's get those young players an
opportunity to go out there and show
what they can do so we can hit the
ground running in the offseason and we
can avoid this feeling next year.
>> So again, the big news, uh, we heard
from coach talking about Patrick Mahomes
injured on the last drive. Um, a lot of
injuries in this game to add to the
whole bunch of injuries that were coming
into this game, but an MRI on Patrick's
knee tomorrow. So, we won't know
anything until then. Uh, and again, they
got probably swelling going down, but
we'll close this way in this game. We
got three more games here, but it's
trusting the infrastructure, even tr
trusting the uh medical staff and the
athletic training staff that surrounds
Mahomes. We've seen him do do it before
with his knee uh back all the way back
in 2019. You trust your infrastructure.
This is a strong infrastructure. This is
not a group uh that is used to this, but
we've seen them rally time and time
again, and uh that's where our trust is.
>> Yeah, it sure is. This season hasn't
been what we expected or anticipated,
but I trust everyone in this building
wholeheartedly to get this thing on the
right track. It's all about collectively
sticking together and moving forward.
I'm proud of this team for how they
played this year. Uh the cards didn't
fall our way, but all you can do is move
forward, evaluate, and try to attack
next year. I have no doubt we'll be
where we belong next year, but this
feeling right now, this hurts. And you
know, as Patrick Mahomes says, it's
supposed to hurt. But that's why we have
these people in our building that uh
they're going to remember this feeling
here today and we're not going to be in
this position next year.
>> You could still win three games and go 9
and eight. That would keep a winning
streak alive. The Chiefs have never had
a losing season under Andy Reid. So
>> go beat the Titans. Who knows? Let's go.
Anyway, he's Matt McMullen. We will keep
you [music] up to speed all week,
especially with Patrick Mahomes
condition with all of our shows that you
can follow us all week long. However you
love to follow us. But the Chiefs lose
it here 16-13 to the Chargers default to
6 and8 on the season. And now we go into
new territory this week as we take the
Titans take on the Titans next week in
Nashville. [music] For Matt McMullen,
I'm Mitch Holtus. Thanks for joining us
on this edition of Chiefs Rewind. Chiefs
Rewind is brought to you by Ford, the
official car and truck of the Kansas
City Chiefs, and by Community America
Credit Union, the official banking
partner of the Kansas City Chiefs.